Keen Wilson

keencwilson@gmail.com | (913) 242-2528 | Olympia, WA 98501

Github: github.com/keenwilson | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/keenwilson | Portfolio: https://keenwilson.github.io

SUMMARY

Keen has full-stack programming experience designing, writing, and deploying rich web experiences with test coverage on a weekly sprints CI/CD DevOps basis. She works with user interface (HTML, CSS,JavaScript, React, Typescript, Redux), accessibility standards (WCAG, ADA), cloud technologies (AWS), configuration management (Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform), automated testings and CI/CD (Bazel, CodePipeline, GitLab), NodeJs and Python REST APIs, and database relationships and modeling (SQL, NoSQL, ORM).

Keen enjoys working with the entire application stack, collaborating with market-oriented teams to build user-focused applications, solving complicated problems, and delivering clean, functional, well-documented software in a highly collaborative, remote-friendly environment.

EXPERIENCE

Optimally / Software Engineer (Remote)

July 2020 - Nov 2021, Leawood, Kansas

Operational & expense optimization products to Small- and Medium-sized businesses

- Architected, designed, built, and maintained Optimally's responsive progressive-enhanced front-end applications (HTML, JavaScript/React/TypeScript, CSS), Python object-oriented REST APIs, and infrastructure as code
- Prototyped, tested, and deployed front-end dashboards for data visualization using highly interactive data-driven visualization grammar for statistical charts
- Continuously collaborated with product development team to drive value for customers; drove quality by owning end-to-end software development, testing automation, and coding practices
- Ensured platform security through Security Best Practice knowledge; implemented DevOps techniques and processes to improve platform quality, cost-effectiveness, and product feedback loop

Finsignum / Software Engineer

February 2019 - July 2020, Prairie Village, Kansas

Healthcare financial forecasting software as a service

- Contributed application code ranging from building secure, scalable web applications to authenticate users, securely store data, and user metadata, authorize selective access to data, and executing server-side code
- Developed and maintained data processing microservices with Lambda, Serverless, and EC2 Compute, S3 Storage, EMR Analytics, CloudFormation, VPC, and API Gateway Networking, and Content Delivery, SES, SNS, and SQS Application Integration, IAM and Cognito Security, Identity, & Compliance
- Refactored a private Python library contains common code and content that is used in multiple Lambda functions
- Wrote automated testing in JavaScript (Jest, Enzyme) and Python (unittest) and documented weekly changelog to convey noteworthy changes to stakeholders

Sabbatical / Freelance Web Developer

June 2016 - February 2019, Kansas City, Missouri

Three-year sabbatical to raise two small children in three different cities around the world i.e., Bangkok, New York City, and Kansas City

- Created static marketing websites with HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Volunteered as a volunteer mentor to help beginners learn how to build web applications at Coding & Cocktails, an introductory coding series organized by Kansas City Women in Technology

Wunderman Thompson (formerly JWT Bangkok) / Account Manager October 2015 - June 2016, Bangkok, Thailand Part of the WPP Group, one of the world's largest communications corporations.

 Managed cross-functional teams on projects which created promotional materials for consumer goods clients across Southeast Asia, and was involved in Social Media Marketing, and Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina Kenan-Flagler Business School / MBA University of Kansas / Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Chulalongkorn University / BA in Communication Arts (GPA 3.65)

Chapel Hill, North Carolina Overland Park, Kansas Bangkok, Thailand